Ben Hubbard

Head of Customer Success

07825775797

► ben@benhubbard.co.uk

Linkedin

Website

Leader in customer experience with extensive intersectional expertise in product marketing, customer success, support, and enablement. Committed to creating and growing outstanding customer success functions and strategies, I frequently write about customer success strategies and best practices on my <u>website</u>.

Highlights at MessageBird:

- Exceeded churn rate target: Q3 2021 with a net churn of 1.7% against an 18% forecast, and 2022 with 3.6% churn against a 9% target.
- Managing a portfolio of~\$5.2m.
- Directly responsible for \$150k expansion revenue in 2022 Q2+3 and \$150k in 2023 to date.
- Contributed to a further \$250k of expansion in revenue-supporting sales.

Experience

<u>MessageBird</u> (Acquired Taxi for Email) / Lead Customer Success Manager / Account Manager

September 2018 - Present

- Grew from a Customer Success, Support and Education Manager and was promoted into a Customer Success Lead for the Taxi for Email product.
 From early 2023, became an Account Manager, responsible for \$125k expansion every quarter and 100% renewals (annual \$5m BoB) in 2023.
- Maximized financial potential by identifying opportunities across my book of business and providing subject matter expertise to close the deals, leading to \$350K in upsell revenue in 2022.
- Developed and built a customer onboarding process as part of the broader customer journey strategy.
- Re-designed the team structure and ticketing process to reduce first-line support tickets whilst providing customer education to domain experts to decrease reliance on escalations.
- Fostered collaboration and built relationships with key stakeholders cross-functionally from C-Suite to Sales & Marketing to align on their goals for Taxi and provided advisory.
- Managed a team of 3 through the acquisition and provided mentorship, subject matter expertise and coaching.
- Analysed usage data and identified risk factors such as low customer usage of the main product features to create a rescue plan, highlighting the business value and impact of utilising the product.
- Initiated a **clear pathway for user feedback** to be incorporated into the product roadmap.

<u>GatherContent</u> / Product Marketing Manager / Customer Success Manager July 2015 - August 2018

- Promoted from a Customer Success Manager to a Product Marketing Manager to communicate the product's value to customers and convert them into leads.
- Conducted customer interviews to **update the customer journey**.
- Audited the marketing funnel to gain actionable insights, which led to

- doubling the conversion rate to ~20%.
- Produced case studies and customer enablement content to drive the bottom of the funnel and the adoption of new features.
- Managed the help centre documentation, produced new content, and refined existing content.
- Resolved customer inquiries through Intercom, providing expertise on broad topics from technical questions to billing, achieving an average of 98% or rating for conversations.
- **Designed and implemented** the customer onboarding experience, utilising in-app messages and email to deliver helpful communication.
- Facilitated weekly webinars to teach customers how to use the product.
- Enhanced my knowledge of email drip, segmentation, automation, paid social ads, content distribution, content personalisation and image/video editing by providing support in those areas.

PAYMILL / Marketing Manager, UK

February 2014 - July 2015

- Oversaw UK marketing activities for PAYMILL, including negotiating event sponsorship, representing PAYMILL at events and contributing to strategic marketing decisions, which included leading two key product launches.
- Key Account Management in the UK.

Almath Crucibles Limited / Sales & Marketing Manager

January 2012 - January 2014

 Spearheaded email marketing, CRM, SEO, analytics, key account management and building out the sales process to streamline orders and support customer retention.

Education

Anglia Ruskin University / BSc (Hons.) Sports Coaching & Physical Education (2:1)

ProductLed /PoductLed Growth Certified

June 2021

MEDDICC / MEDDPICC Masterclass V2

May 2023

Tools

Customer Success: Salesforce, Hubspot, Strikedeck, Quip, Zapier, ClientSuccess, Mixpanel, Looker, Mode, Calendly, Intercom, JIRA.

CMS & marketing platforms: Shopify, Wordpress, Big Cartel, Magento, Statamic, ActiveCampaign, Drip, Mailchimp, Braze, MessageBird.

Web dev: HTML, CSS, Liquid, JS, Adobe Creative Suite, Sketch, Jekyll, Figma.

Outside of work

Run Lead & Co-Captain / TrackEast

- Responsible for community management, growing attendance through Instagram and coaching in-person sessions.
- Organising track sessions weekly in collaboration with the leadership team.
- Leveraging my experience as a qualified England Athletics run leader.